Mss.B.L493
American Philosophical Society
- Correspondence, 7.0 Linear feet 17 upright boxes, 1 oversized folder, 1 digital record. (Box 1-17)
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, Feb. 25, 1878; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Rogers, William Barton, 1804-1882
    Boston, A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Thanks for his photograph. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, Philadelphia, Feb. 28, 1878; 8x5; Putnam, F. W., (Frederic Ward), 1839-1915
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers Thanks for photograph. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, March 4, 1878; 8x5; Hayden, F. V. (Ferdinand Vandeveer), 1829-1887
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers Wants his article for a publication. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [J.L.] Leconte, March 10, 1878; 8" x 10"; Hayden, F. V. (Ferdinand Vandeveer), 1829-1887
  - Letter to John L. Leconte, March 16, 1878; 8x5; Henshaw, Samuel, 1852-1941
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p.,end. Note on reverse pertaining to entomological publications by Le Conte. (see Le Conte papers.) Asks to borrow a publication. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [John L.] LeConte, Mar. 30, 1878; Hall, James
  - Letter to J.L. Leconte, April 14, 1878; 8" x 10 1/2"; Bolter, A.
    Chicago, A.(?) L.S. End. by J.L. Le Conte.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, April 23, 1878; 7 1/2" x 9 3/4"; Le Duc, William Gates, 1823-1917
    Washington, L.S. 1p. Contains end. by J.L.Le Conte.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], April 25, 1878; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Candèze, E. C. (Ernest Charles), 1827-1898
    Liege, A.L.S. 4p. In French. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomological research.
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, May 4, 1878; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Collis, Charles H. T. (Charles Henry Tucky), 1838-1902
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Will try to help him. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. LeConte, May 8, 1878; Blanchard, Frederick
  - Letter to T.L. Le Conte, May 22, 1878; 5" x 8"; Blanchard, Frederick
    Lowell, Mass., A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], May 27, 1878; 5" x 8"; Schwartz, Eugene Amandus, 1844-1928
    Detroit, A.L.S. 3p. End. by J.L. LeC.
  - Letter to [John L. LeConte], May 29, 1878; Blanchard, Frederick
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], June 8, 1878; 5" x 8"; Schwartz, Eugene Amandus, 1844-1928
    Detroit, A.L.S. 4p.
  - Letter to [John L. LeConte], June 15, 1878
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], June 26, 1878; 5 1/4" x 8 1/4"; Horn, George Henry, 1840-1897
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, July 2, 1878; 7 1/2" x 10"; Belfrage, G. W.
  - Letter to J. L. Le Conte, July 12, 1878; 7 1/2" x 9 3/4"; King, Valentine Overton, 1833-1917
    Austin, A.L.S. 4p. illus.
  - Letter to [John L. LeConte], July 21, 1878
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, July 23, 1878; 5 1/4" x 8 1/4"; Linter, Joseph Albert, 1822-1898
    Albany, A.L.S. 1P. End. in J.L. Le C' hand.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], July 27, 1878; 5 1/4" x 8 1/4"; Horn, George Henry, 1840-1897
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], Aug. 4, 1878; 5 1/4" x 8 1/4"; Horn, George Henry, 1840-1897
  - Letter to [John L.] Leconte, Sept., 1878; 8x5; Blüthner, Moritz Schaufuss
    A.L.S. 3p. In German. (see Le Conte papers.)
  - Letter to [John L. LeConte], Oct. 22, 1878; Blanchard, Frederick
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], Oct. 28, 1878; 8" x 10"; Schwartz, Eugene Amandus, 1844-1928
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, Oct. 28, 1878(?); 4 1/2" x 7"; Matthews, A. (Andrew), 1815-1897
    Gumley (?) A.L.S. 4p. End. by J.L. Le Conte.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Nov. 5, 1878; 7x4-1/2; Sharp, David, 1840-1922
    A.L.S. 3p.,end. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomological specimens of the U.S.
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, Nov. 8, 1878; 7x4-1/2; Hubbard, H. G., (Henry Guernsey), 1850-1899
    Detroit, A.L.S. 3p. (see Le Conte papers.) Concerning politics in the department of agriculture. Entomological matters. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [J.L.?] Le Conte, Nov. 9, 1878; 8" x 10"; Riley, Charles V., (Charles Valentine), 1843-1895
    Washington, A(?)L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, Nov. 11, 1878; 8" x 10"; Schwartz, Eugene Amandus, 1844-1928
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Nov. 13, 1878; 8x5 and 8-1/2x5-1/2; Foote, Albert E., 1846-1895
    A.L.S. 2p.and enc.of 1p. and (see Le Conte papers.) Lists books sold and forwards check.
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, Dec. 11, 1878; 5" x 8"; Guyot, A. (Arnold), 1807-1884
    Princeton, A.L.S. 2p. End. by J.L. Le Conte.
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, Philadelphia, Dec. 28, 1878; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Riley, Charles V., (Charles Valentine), 1843-1895
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Difficulty of contacting a man in the field. Will send entomological specimen. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, Jan. 2, 1879; 5" x 8"; Leland, Charles Godfrey, 1824-1903
    [Philadelphia?] A.L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, Jan. 8, 1879; 5" x 8"; Blanchard, Frederick
    Lowell, Mass., A.L.S. 6p.
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, Jan. 23, 1879; 8" x 10"; Riley, Charles V., (Charles Valentine), 1843-1895
  - Letter to [John L. LeConte], Feb. 4, 1879; Blanchard, Frederick
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, Feb. 23, 1879; 8" x 10"; Goldsmith, Middleton, 1818-1887
    Rutland, A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], Feb. 27, 1879; 5" x 8"; Hayden, F. V. (Ferdinand Vandeveer), 1829-1887
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], March 3, 1879; 10x8; Goldsmith, Middleton, 1818-1887
    Rutland, Vt., A.L.S. 4p. (see Le Conte paper Study of alkaloids. Medicine. Originally B L493.4
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, April 5, 1879; 8" x 10"; Riley, Charles V., (Charles Valentine), 1843-1895
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], April 29, 1879; 4 3/4" x 7"; Sharp, David, 1840-1922
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], April 29, 1879; 5" x 8"; Ulke, Henry, 1821-
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], April 30, 1879; 4 3/4" x 7"; Sharp, David, 1840-1922
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, May 1, 1879; 5" x 8"; Hagen, Hermann August, 1817-1893
  - Letter to John L. Leconte, May 3, 1879; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], May 26, 1879; 4 3/4" x 7"; Sharp, David, 1840-1922
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], May 29, 1879; 8x5; Ulke, Henry, 1821-
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers Has finished portrait of Joseph Henry. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, May 31, 1879; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Linter, Joseph Albert, 1822-1898
    Albany, A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomology. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, June 7, 1879; 8-1/2x4-1/2; Hagen, Hermann August, 1817-1893
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomology. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, June 7, 1879; 8" x 10"; Smith, Emily A. (Emily Anna), 1840-
    Peoria,Ill., A.L.S. 1p. Note by J.L. LeC.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], June 17, 1879; 8-1/4x5-1/4; How, G. H.
  - Letter to [John Huntington Crane] Coffin, June 23, 1879; 8x4-3/4; Holden, Edward Singleton, 1846-1914
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Regrets "there are none on hand to offer to Prof. Le Conte." On same leaf is: Coffin to Le Conte; [June 1879]. Originally B L493.4
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, June 26, 1879; 8x5; Hagen, Hermann August, 1817-1893
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, June 27, 1879; 5" x 8"; Billings, John S. (John Shaw), 1838-1913
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, June, 1879; 8x4-3/4; Coffin, J.H.C. (John Huntington Crane), 1815-1890.
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Could not procure a photograph of Saturn. On same sheet as: Holden to Coffin; June 23, 1879. Originally B L493.4
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, July 12, 1879; 8x5; Siewers, Charles G., 1815-1882
    Newport, Ky., A.L.S. 4p. (see Le Conte papers) Entomology of Kentucky. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, July 21, 1879; 8x5; Newsom, F. S.
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Le Conte papers Concerning the Le Contes of Florida.
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, July 30, 1879; 8x5; Barker, George F[rederick, 1836-1910
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers Asks that he show a friend through the U.S. Mint. Originally B L493.4
  - List of insects, July, 1879; 6-1/4x3-3/4; Siewers, Charles G., 1815-1882
    D. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le conte, Aug. 2, 1879; 4 1/2" x 7"; Sclater, Philip Lutley, 1829-1913
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, Aug. 4, 1879; 5 1/4" x 8 1/4"; Harris, Thaddeus William, 1795-1856
  - Letter to [John L. LeConte], Aug. 4, 1879; Harrison, George L.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Aug. 17, 1879; 8" x 10"; Schwartz, Eugene Amandus, 1844-1928
    Columbus, Texas, A.L.S. 6p.
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, Aug. 26, 1879; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Sennett, George B. (George Burritt), 1840-1900
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Wants an article on insects. Originally B L493.4
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], Sept. 16, 1879; 5" x 8"; Ulke, Henry, 1821-
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Sept. 19, 1879; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Schwartz, Eugene Amandus, 1844-1928
    Washington, A.L.S. 5p.
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, Sept. 21, 1879; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Riley, Charles V., (Charles Valentine), 1843-1895
  - Letter to [John L. LeConte], Sept. 26, 1879; Blanchard, Frederick
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Philadelphia, Sept. 27, 1879; 10x8; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p., end.: "Specimens names: of no value: subsequent correspondence discouraged." (see Le Conte papers) Sends insects collected in Mexico by Mr. Wilkinson and asks that he identify them. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Sept. 30, 1879; 11x8-1/2; Chapuis, F. (Félicien), 1824-1879
    Heusy, Printed L. 1p. In French. (see Le Conte papers.) Notification of the death of Félicien Chapuis. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, Oct. 2, 1879; 8-1/4x5; Scudder, Samuel Hubbard, 1837-1911
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Asks for information about his library. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], Oct. 2, 1879; 5" x 8"; Ulke, Henry, 1821-
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, Philadelphia, Oct. 3, 1879; 10x8; Smithsonian Institution.
    Washington, A.L.S.: S.F.Baird. 1p.,end. (see Le Conte papers.) Asks identification of Mexican insects collected by E. Wilkinson, Jr. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, Oct. 9, 1879; 5" x 8"; Hayden, F. V. (Ferdinand Vandeveer), 1829-1887
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Oct. 9, 1879; 8" x 10"; Schwartz, Eugene Amandus, 1844-1928
  - Letter to John L. Le conte, Oct. 10, 1879; 8" x 10"; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887
    New York, L. 1p.
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, Oct. 10, 1879; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Schwartz, Eugene Amandus, 1844-1928
    Washington, A.L.S. 6p.
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, Oct. 11, 1879; 7 1/2" x 9 1/2"; Coues, Elliott, 1842-1899
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, Oct. 14, 1879; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Schwartz, Eugene Amandus, 1844-1928
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, Oct. 14, 1879; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Scudder, Samuel Hubbard, 1837-1911
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomology. Concerning his library. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], Oct. 15, 1879; 5" x 8"; Schaupp, F. G.
    Brooklyn, A.L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Oct. 19, 1879; 8x5; Hagen, Hermann August, 1817-1893
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 3p. (see Le Conte papers.) His entomological work. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, Oct. 19, 1879; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Schwartz, Eugene Amandus, 1844-1928
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, Oct. 20, 1879; 7 1/2" x 9 1/2"; Coues, Elliott, 1842-1899
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], Oct. 20, 1879; 5" x 8"; Ulke, Henry, 1821-
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, Philadelphia, Oct. 22, 1879; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Coues, Elliott, 1842-1899
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Hayden will have to decide if illustrations can be furnished for his paper. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to J. A. Lintner, Albany, Oct. 22, 1879; 9-1/2x6; Hoey, Nicholas J.
    New Orleans, A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Forwards insects for identification. On same sheet is letter from Lintner to Le Conte; Oct. 27, 1879. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Oct. 23, 1879; 8" x 10"; Comstock, John Henry, 1849-1931
    Washington, L.S. 1p. Notes by J.L. Le Conte (?)
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, Oct. 23, 1879; 5 1/2" x 9 1/2"; Forbes, Stephen Alfred, 1844-1930
    Normal, Ill., A.L.S. 5p.
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, Oct. 25, 1879; 7 1/2" x 9 1/2"; Coues, Elliott, 1842-1899
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, Oct. 27, 1879; 9-1/2x6; Linter, Joseph Albert, 1822-1898
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Forwards insects for identification. On same sheet as Hoey to Linton; Oct. 22, 1879.
  - Letter to John L. LeConte, Oct. 28, 1879; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Schwartz, Eugene Amandus, 1844-1928
    Washington, D.C., A.L.S. 2p. Deposited by the Academy of Natural Sciences, Oct. 1948.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], Oct. 29, 1879; 4 1/2" x 7"; Sharp, David, 1840-1922
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, Oct. 31, 1879; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Schwartz, Eugene Amandus, 1844-1928
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, Nov. 1, 1879; 9-1/2x6; Forbes, Stephen Alfred, 1844-1903
    Normal, Ill., A.L.S. 4p. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomology. Originally B L493.4
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, Nov. 4, 1879; 7 1/2" x 9 1/2"; Coues, Elliott, 1842-1899
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, Nov. 6, 1879; 5" x 8"; Belfrage, G. W.
    Clifton,Texas, A.L.S. 2p. Note by J.L. Le Conte.
  - Letter to J. L. Le Conte, Nov. 6, 1879; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Riley, Charles V., (Charles Valentine), 1843-1895
    Washington, L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, Nov. 8, 1879; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Schwartz, Eugene Amandus, 1844-1928
  - Letter to [J.L. ?] Le Conte, Nov. 9, 1879; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Riley, Charles V., (Charles Valentine), 1843-1895
  - Letter to [Charles Valentine] Riley, Nov. 11, 1879; 8x5-1/4; Le Conte, John L. (John Lawrence), 1825-1883
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. Draft. (see Le Conte papers.) Will contribute articles to the new magazine. Concerning the seizure of certain entomological specimens.
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, Nov. 13, 1879; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Schwartz, Eugene Amandus, 1844-1928
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, Nov. 14, 1879; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Schwartz, Eugene Amandus, 1844-1928
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], Nov. 14, 1879; 5" x 8"; Ulke, Henry, 1821-
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, Nov. 15, 1879; 7 3/4" x 12 1/2"; Mische, William
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, Nov. 18, 1879; 5" x 8"; Scudder, Samuel Hubbard, 1837-1911
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, Nov. 19, 1879; 7 1/2" x 9 1/2"; Coues, Elliott, 1842-1899
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Leconte, Nov. 21, 1879; 7-3/4x5; Edwards, Henry, 1830-1891
    New York, A.L.S. 3p. (see Le Conte papers.) Will miss him in Boston, but his wife will show Le Conte his entomological collection. Refers to A. Agassiz.
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, Nov. 28, 1879; 5" x 8"; Nason, William A.
    Algonquin,Ill., A.L.S. 4p.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], Dec. 9, 1879; 5" x 8"; Schaupp, F. G.
    Brooklyn, A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Dec. 11, 1879; 5" x 8"; Crawford, John Martin, 1845-1916
  - Letter to John [L. Le Conte], Dec. 20, 1879; 5" x 8"; LeConte, Joseph, 1823-1901
    Berkeley, Cal., A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, Dec. 26, 1879; 5" x 8"; Winsor, Justin, 1831-1897
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], Dec. 31, 1879; 5 3/4" x 9"; Wells, Francis
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], 1879; 4 1/2" x 7"; Agassiz, Alexander, 1835-1910
    Cambridge, Monday (?) A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Jan. 1, 1880; 8 1/2" x 10 1/2"; American Academy of Arts and Sciences
    Boston, Printed form. 1p.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], Jan. 1, 1880; 5" x 8"; Blanchard, Frederick
    Lowell, A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to John [L. Le Conte], Jan. 5, 1880; 5" x 8"; LeConte, Joseph, 1823-1901
    Berkeley, Cal., A.L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to J.L. Leconte, Jan. 10, 1880; 5" x 8"; Smith, Robert Pearsall, 1827-1898
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, Jan. 13, 1880; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Clarke, Thomas Curtis, 1827-1901
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Forwards an item.
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, Jan. 16, 1880; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; King, Valentine Overton, 1833-1917
    Austin, Texas, A.L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, Jan. 18, 1880; 5" x 8"; King, Valentine Overton, 1833-1917
    Austin, Tex., (?) A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Jan. 20, 1880; 8x5; Schaupp, F. G.
    Brooklyn, N.Y., A.L.S. 4p. (see Le Conte papers Entomology. Friendly letter. Originally B L493.4
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, Jan. 20, 1880; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Schwartz, Eugene Amandus, 1844-1928
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Jan. 22, 1880; 8x5; Nichols, J. H.
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers Invites him to tea and conversation with Brinton, etc.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Jan. 26, 1880; 8x5-1/4; How, G. H.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S.with initials. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Comments on entomological questions.
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, Jan. 28, 1880; 5" x 8"; Siewers, Charles G., 1815-1882
    Newport, A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Feb. 2, [1880?]; 5" x 3"; Bolter, A
    Chicago, A.L.S. postal card - 1p. and add.
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, Feb. 4, 1880; 4 3/4" x 7"; Furness, Horace Howard, 1833-1912
    [Philadelphia] (?). A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, Feb. 7, 1880; 5" x 8"; King, Valentine Overton, 1833-1917
    Austin, Tex., A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to [John L. LeConte], Feb. 8, 1880; Blanchard, Frederick
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, Feb. 10, 1880; 5" x 10"; Nason, William A.
    Algonquin,Ill., A.L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Feb. 18, 1880; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Schwartz, Eugene Amandus, 1844-1928
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, Feb. 18, 1880; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Schwartz, Eugene Amandus, 1844-1928
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Feb. 21, 1880; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Raeloft, W.
    Brussels, A.L.S. 3p. In French. (see Le Conte papers.) Forwards specimens of insects.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], Feb., 1880; 8" x 10 1/2"; Bolter, A
    Chicago, A(?) L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, March 5, 1880; 8" x 10"; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, March 12, 1880; 5" x 8"; King, Valentine Overton, 1833-1917
    Austin, A.L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, March 16, 1880; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Schwartz, Eugene Amandus, 1844-1928
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], March 22, 1880; 5" x 8"; Grote, Augustus Radcliffe, 1841-1903
    Buffalo, A.L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, March 22, 1880; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Schwartz, Eugene Amandus, 1844-1928
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. Contains also a note in J.L. Le Conte's hand
  - Letter to John [L.] Le Conte, March 25, 1880; 5 3/4" x 9"; Smith, Emily A. (Emily Anna), 1840-
  - Letter to [J.L.] Leconte, March 26, 1880; 5" x 8"; Sallé, Aug., (Auguste), 1820-1896
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, March 28, 1880; 8" x 10"; Riley, Charles V., (Charles Valentine), 1843-1895
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le conte, March 30, 1880; 5" x 8"; Linter, Joseph Albert, 1822-1898
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, April 2, 1880; 5" x 8"; Scudder, Samuel Hubbard, 1837-1911
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, April 13, 18[80?]; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Schwartz, Eugene Amandus, 1844-1928
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, April 16, 1880; 5" x 8"; Bell, Robert
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, April 19, 1880; 8" x 10 1/2"; Bolter, A
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], April 28, 1880; 5" x 8"; Bell, Robert
    Montreal, A.L.S. 2p. End. by J.L. Le Conte.
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, May 11, 1880; 5" x 8"; Bell, Robert
    Montreal, A.L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], May 14, 1880; 4 1/2" x 7"; Sharp, David, 1840-1922
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, May 26, 1880; 8" x 10"; Linter, Joseph Albert, 1822-1898
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, June 10, 1880; 5 1/2" x 8 1/2"; Linter, Joseph Albert, 1822-1898
    Albany, A.L.S. 2p. End. by J.L. Le Conte.
  - Letter to John [L. Le Conte], June 19, 1880; 8x5; LeConte, Joseph, 1823-1901
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers Hopes to visit him in Philadelphia on the way South. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, June 25, 1880; 8x5-1/4; Saunders, William, 1822-1900
    London, Canada, A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Concerning his article on Riley. Hagen also has an article on Riley. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], June 28, 1880; 4 1/2" x 7"; Waller, Gerald
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, July 6, 1880; 5 1/4" x 8 1/2"; Waller, Gerald
    New York, A.L.S. 2 leaves
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], July 20, 1880; 8x5; Blanchard, Frederick
    Dowell, Mass., A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers Sent insects. Entomology. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, July 23, 1880; 5" x 8"; Hagen, Hermann August, 1817-1893
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, Aug. 13, 1880; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Riley, Charles V., (Charles Valentine), 1843-1895
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. End. by L.L. LeC.
  - Letter to [C.V.] Riley, Aug. 14, 1880; 7 1/2" x 8 3/4"; Le Conte, John L. (John Lawrence), 1825-1883
    Philadelphia, Letterpress copy of A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, Aug. 16, 1880; 8" x 10"; Riley, Charles V., (Charles Valentine), 1843-1895
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, Aug. 18, 1880; 8x5; Crotch, G. K.
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Le Conte papers Concerning the expedition and comments on coleoptera, etc. collected.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte?], Aug. 23, 1880; 5" x 8"; Siewers, Charles G., 1815-1882
    Newport, A.L.S. 4p.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Aug. 29, 1880; 8x5; Blüthner, M.
    Lockford, A.L.S. 3p. In German (see Le Conte papers.) Entomology of the west. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], Sept. 2, 1880; 4 1/2" x 7"; Currie, C. George
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, Sept. 8, 1880; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Hare, R. Emett
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Inquires about the health of a doctor form Philadelphia.
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, Philadelphia, Sept. 16, 1880; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Borre, A. de
    Brussels, A.L.S. 2p. In French. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomological news.
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, Sept. 22, 1880; 8x5; Rivers, J. J.
    Berkeley, Cal.; A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers Entomology. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, Philadelphia, Sept. 23, 1880; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Kansas Academy of Science. Popenoe, Edwin A
    Manhattan, Kan., A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Asks if he would like to contribute an entomological articel to the Kansas Academy of Science. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, Philadelphia, Sept. 23, 1880; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Popenoe, Edwin A.
    Manhattan, Kan., A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Asks if he would like to contribue an entomoligical article to the Kansas Academy of Science. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, Oct. 15, 1880; 5" x 8"; Hagen, Hermann August, 1817-1893
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Oct. 22, 1880; 5" x 8"; Morrison, Herbart Knowles
    Morganton, N.C., A.L.S. 4p.
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, Oct. 30, 1880; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Schwartz, Eugene Amandus, 1844-1928
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, Nov. 5, 1880; 5 1/4" x 8 1/4"; King, Valentine Overton, 1833-1917
    Austin, Texas, A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, Nov. 30, 1880; 5 1/2" x 9"; Hubbard, H. G., (Henry Guernsey), 1850-1899
    Detroit, A.L.S. 3p. Contains note by J.L. Le Conte.
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, Dec. 9, 1880; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Schwartz, Eugene Amandus, 1844-1928
  - Letter to John [L. Le Conte], Dec. 12, 1880; 5" x 8"; LeConte, Joseph, 1823-1901
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, Dec. 14, 1880; 73 /4" x 9 3/4"; Riley, Charles V., (Charles Valentine), 1843-1895
  - Letter to John [L.] Leconte, Dec. 15, 1880; 5" x 8"; Leland, Charles Godfrey, 1824-1903
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, Dec. 30, 1880; 5 1/2" x 9"; Hubbard, H. G., (Henry Guernsey), 1850-1899
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Feb. 4, 1881; 8x5; Hamlin, Augustus C. (Augustus Choate), 1829-1905